Yuya Tinnefeld

Cloud DevOps Engineer

Phone: (+49) 1797908144

Email: yuyatinnefeld@gmail.com

Address: Düsseldorf

yuyatinnefeld.com

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Python, Go, Shell, SQL

Cloud Provider

GCP, AWS

DevOps

Kubernetes, Docker, Terraform, Gitlab, GitHub, ArgoCD, Prometheus, Grafana

Data Engineering / Big Data

PostgreSQL, MySQL, BigQuery, Snowflake, Spark, Hadoop, Airflow, InfluxDB, Kafka, MongoDB

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Japanese (Native Language) German (Fluent, C2) English (Business, C1)

CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

HashiCorp Terraform HashiCorp Vault Prometheus

SUMMARY/OBJECTIVE

Passionate Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience in data engineering and backend systems. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Experienced in working with both small and large teams across multiple projects and companies. I always loved the tickle of excitement that you get, when you jump heads on into a new project. While diving deeper into this versatile technology, it just amazes me over and over again.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cloud DevOps Engineer // REWE digital, Cologne

07/2021 - Today

- CI/CD for Backend & Frontend Apps (Docker, k8s, Gitlab CI)
- IaC Integration (Terraform)
- Data Pipeline Development (Spark, Dataproc, Airflow)
- Application Development (FastAPI, Cloud Run, GCE)
- Service Migration from On-Premise on GCP
- Logging and Monitoring (GCP)

Marketing Data Analyst & Engineer // Publics Media, Düsseldorf 03/2018 - 06/2021

- Data Engineering (Flask, Pandas, Selenium)
- Data Analysis & Tracking (GA, BigQuery, Jupyter)
- Projekt Management, Workshops, Consulting

Web Analyst & SEO // RTL Interactive, Cologne

09/2017 - 02/2018

- Web Analytics (Google Analytics)
- Search Engine Optimization (On- and Off Page)

Student Trainee & Internship // network.publishing, Cologne

12/2016 - 08/2017

- Web Analytics (Google Analytics)
- Data Warehouse & Data Mining

ECommerce Startup CEO & CTO // Wanamour, Cologne

11/2014 - 06/2022

- Management
- Web Development & Web Design
- Marketing

EDUCATION

University of applied sciences Bonn-Rhein-Sieg

B.Sc. Business information systems

09/2013 - 08/2017

Focus area: Business Intelligence (Data-Warehouse, Data Mining, Predictive Analysis, Decision Support System





HashiCorp Cloud Engineer Certifications

Certifies that

Yuya Tinnefeld

has successfully met the requirements of a

Vault Associate

HCVA0-002

May 06, 2023

Date Issued

Mitchell Hashimoto

Armon Dadgar

Armon Dadgar

b3a68d4b-eb8e-494e-ao2a-d2131246f9b5

Certificate Number



The Cloud Native Computing Foundation hereby certifies that

Yuya Tinnefeld

has successfully completed the program requirements to be recognized as a

Prometheus Certified Associate

July 24, 2023

LF-dxc73gh27j

DATE OF COMPLETION

CERTIFICATE ID NUMBER





HashiCorp Certifies that

Yuya Tinnefeld

Has successfully met the requirements of a

Terraform Associate

2023-03-11

Date Issued

Mitchell Hashimoto

Armon Dadaar